<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>41123237協同產品設計實習 - 41123237 W10</title><link href="./" rel="alternate"></link><link href="./feeds/41123237-w10.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>./</id><updated>2024-04-25T16:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>41123237 W10</title><link href="./41123237%20W10.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-25T16:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-04-25T08:47:34+08:00</updated><author><name>kmol</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-04-25:./41123237 W10.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2024 協同產品設計實習課程第十週內容&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2024 協同產品設計實習課程第十週內容&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;請下載&lt;a href="https://nfuedu-my.sharepoint.com/:f:/g/personal/41123237_nfu_edu_tw/EpnSw5gfw9ZLq8KWnm9EFgIBzsErrkSQoKyUua7nTI9Uwg?e=cFY2CV"&gt;cd2024_ball_balancing_platform_control_ref.7z&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;閱讀後請將摘要內容放入個人與分組網誌中&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;摘要&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在動態系統領域操作時，控制理論及其應用至關重要。對於固有不穩定或半穩定的系統，補償干擾和外部作用是必要的。通過建造一個實驗裝置作為理論的演示器，進一步比較源自牛頓力學的實際物理和電腦模擬結果。為了進行比較，需要設計一個滿足系統要求的滿意控制器。關於裝置和控制，引入一種比例-積分-微分控制器，用於平衡平台上的球體。進一步允許分析以確定穩定自然不穩定或半穩定系統的限制。還要檢查這些與理論期望之間的差異。
論文中應用的控制是線性的類型，僅能在線性控制的範圍內正常運作。使用標準組件和微控制器，構建了一個裝置來保持平台上的球體。這是通過使用Arduino庫和開源代碼進行編程來實現的。因此，為了研究目的，查看該裝置是否能在控制的線性領域內正常運作。
有了上述說明，本論文將首先通過計算機輔助程序來論述球在平台情境的理論模型。然後將理論結果與從物理建構獲得的結果進行比較。進一步檢查在考慮控制理論和系統實現時為何會出現差異。&lt;br&gt;
關鍵詞— 機電系統、控制理論、平衡、PID、球體、平台、Arduino、伺服&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;原文&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract
Control theory and its applications are crucial when operating
within the area of dynamic systems. Compensating
for disturbances and external actions imposed on a given
system being inherently unstable or semi-stable.
Through the physical construction of a apparatus as
a demonstrator of the theory further comparing the factual
physical and computer simulated results derived from
Newtonian mechanics. To enable comparison, designing a
satisfactory controller capable of fulfilling the requirements
set for the system is necessary. With regards to apparatus
and control, the introduction of a proportional-integralderivative
controller for a system balancing a ball on a platform.
Further allowing for analysis to determine the limitations
when stabilizing a naturally unstable or semi-stable
system. Also, examine how these differ from the theoretical
expectations.
The control applied throughout the thesis is of the type
linear, exclusively being able to operate properly within the
linear spectrum of control. Using standard components and
a microcontroller, a apparatus is constructed to maintain
a ball on a platform. This is executed through programming
with Arduino libraries and open source code. Hence,
for research purposes, to see if the apparatus can operate
satisfactory within the linear domain of control.
With the aforementioned stated, this thesis will first
cover the theoretical model of the ball on platform scenario
through computer aided programs. Then compare the theoretical
results with the results acquired from a physical
construction. Further examine why differences occur considering
control theory and system implementation.
Keywords— mechatronics, control theory, balancing, PID,
ball, platform, Arduino, servo
iii&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="41123237 W10"></category><category term="網誌編寫"></category></entry></feed>